<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Videos on larmic.de</title><link>https://larmic.de/en/videos/</link><description>Recent content in Videos on larmic.de</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 21:28:19 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://larmic.de/en/videos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unit vs Integration Testing</title><link>https://larmic.de/en/videos/unit-vs-integration-testing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 21:28:19 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://larmic.de/en/videos/unit-vs-integration-testing/</guid><description>Note This talk is available in german only.
How dogmatic do you have to be when distinguishing between unit and integration testing? In this talk I show different points of view on this topic and try to break through the existing dogmas.
Team Neusta Freitagsfrühstück (friday breakfast) Note This talk was recorded as part of a Freitagsfrühstück. The Freitagsfrühstück is a regular event of the Team Neusta and serves for further education and the technical exchange among each other.</description></item><item><title>Event Storming</title><link>https://larmic.de/en/videos/event-storming/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 21:25:16 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://larmic.de/en/videos/event-storming/</guid><description>Note This talk is available in german only.
Event Storming is a collaborative workshop method used in software development to visualize and understand complex business processes or requirements. It involves all the people involved, such as developers, project managers, product owners and domain experts.
Advantages It goes fast It is easy to understand It costs little money It serves to gain knowledge Team Neusta Freitagsfrühstück (friday breakfast) Note This talk was recorded as part of a Freitagsfrühstück.</description></item><item><title>Testcontainers</title><link>https://larmic.de/en/videos/testcontainers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 21:19:27 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://larmic.de/en/videos/testcontainers/</guid><description>Note This talk is available in german only.
Testcontainers is a framework that allows to use a database or other things during the test execution. test execution.
Testcontainers uses the Docker Environment for this purpose.
Vorteile A free port is searched for and used A Docker sidecar ryuk takes care of clearing the containers afterwards The framework is supported by all major programming languages Team Neusta Freitagsfrühstück (friday breakfast) Note This talk was recorded as part of a Freitagsfrühstück.</description></item><item><title>First steps into hexagonal architecture</title><link>https://larmic.de/en/videos/hexagonal-architecture/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 19:41:47 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://larmic.de/en/videos/hexagonal-architecture/</guid><description>Note This talk is available in german only.
Domain Driven Design (DDD for short) is an approach to modeling complex software and focuses on the technical aspects. aspects in the foreground. The hexagonal architecture picks up on this concept and integrates the domain-oriented content into the core of the application. The concrete technical implementation (such as database or MQ systems) plays a subordinate role.
In this talk I motivate the implementation of software in a hexagonal architecture.</description></item></channel></rss>